{
    "id": "63327f590fd848139688c1af3911e130",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We still don’t know ………………………. Mars supports life or not.",
            "description": "We use the conjunction whether to introduce an indirect yes/no question.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "as",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Scientists …………………………… that Mars might have supported life in the past.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about people’s beliefs, fears etc.",
            "answers": [
                "suspect",
                "are suspecting",
                "have suspected"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Mars is ………………………… arid and dusty.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "present",
                "presently"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Characteristics like channels on the Martian surface indicates that the planet …………………………….. once very wet.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about a past situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Scientists are …………………………… to learn about the history of water on Mars.",
            "description": "Here eager is used as the complement of a verb of incomplete predication. Adverbs cannot be used like this.",
            "answers": [
                "eager",
                "eagerly",
                "eagerness"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Water is fundamental to the question of whether the planet has ever ……………………….. microbial or some other life.",
            "description": "We make perfect tenses by putting the past participle form of the verb after has or have. ",
            "answers": [
                "support",
                "supported",
                "supporting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Life …………………………… we know it requires water.",
            "description": "We use as before a clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A fisherman once ……………………………… on the banks of a river.",
            "description": "The simple past is common in storytelling. ",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "was living",
                "lived"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………………….. fishing every morning, but could never catch enough fish.",
            "description": "Both the simple past and would + infinitive can be used to talk about past habits.",
            "answers": [
                "would go",
                "went",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. a miserable life.",
            "description": "Led is the past tense of lead.",
            "answers": [
                "led",
                "lead",
                "leads"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Then one day he ………………………………… a big fish.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "catches",
                "caught",
                "has caught"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The fisherman ………………………………. the fish to the market, but no one could pay the price he demanded.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "takes",
                "took",
                "has taken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}